A Finding Aid to the Baxter Art Gallery Records, 1968-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.baxtart
Archives of American Art
Baxter Art Gallery
1968-1990
AAA.baxtart
Archives of American Art
15.1 Linear feet
The records of the Baxter Art Gallery measure 15.1 linear feet and date from 1968 to 1990. The collection documents the activities of the gallery founded by Professor David Smith in 1971 on the campus of the California Institute of Technology in Pasadena, California. Documentation includes administrative records, business correspondence, programs and events, exhibition files, and printed material. There are also three films by artist Lillian Schwartz shown at the gallery.Also included are records of the Pasadena Gallery of Contemporary Arts, which was founded after Baxter Art Gallery closed by former director Jay Bellili.
Baxter Art Gallery.
Biographical/Historical note
Baxter Art Gallery (1971-1985) was an art exhibition space at the California Institute of Technology, Pasedena, Calif., founded by Professor David Smith.
David R. Smith, professor of Literature, established an exhibition program for Caltech in 1968, as part of the Institute Programs Committee. In 1971 Baxter Art Gallery was formally established as part of the new Donald E. Baxter Hall of the Humanities and Social Sciences. The majority of the exhibitions focused on contemporary art, with a special interest in Southern California artists and art and technology. David Smith became the first gallery director. After years of struggling to find funding for exhibitions, in 1977 the gallery received sponsorship from the Pasadena Art Alliance. Also around this time the establishment of a membership program, Friends of the Baxter Art Gallery, allowed for more educational programs for the exhibitions, such as lectures, informal talks, films, tours, and performances.
Michael H. Smith served as director from 1977 to 1982, followed by Jay Belloli, director from 1982 to 1985. In 1984 the closing of the gallery was announced, despite outcry from faculty and the public. The last exhibition “25 Years of Space Photography” was held at the gallery from May 22 to September 2, 1985. That exhibition continued to tour internationally to over 50 museums under the curatorship of Jay Belloli.
After Baxter Art Gallery closed Belloli established the Pasadena Gallery of Contemporary Arts and worked to find a new exhibition space. This gallery in collaboration with the Pasadena Arts Workshop became the Armory Center for the Arts in 1989 and Belloli served as Director of Gallery Programs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The records were donated in 1986 by the Baxter Art Gallery via David Smith and Jay Belloli, Directors, and in 1991 by David Grether, chair of the Division of Humanities at the California Institute of Technology. Additional records were donated in 2011 by Jay Belloli.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 7 series.
Series 1: Administrative Records, 1971-1987 (3.3 linear feet; Boxes 1-4)
Series 2: Business Correspondence, 1969-1988 (0.5 linear feet; Box 4)
Series 3: Programs and Events, 1977-1986 (0.4 linear feet; Boxes 4-5)
Series 4: Exhibition Files, 1968-1990 (9.0 linear feet; Boxes 5-14)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1971-1987 (0.5 linear feet; Box 14, OV 16)
Series 6: Pasadena Gallery of Contemporary Arts Records, 1981-1987 (1.3 linear feet; Boxes 14-15)
Series 7: Motion Picture Film, circa 1970, circa 1975 (3 folders; Box 15)
Scope and Contents note
The records of the Baxter Art Gallery measure 15.1 linear feet and date from 1968 to 1990. The collection documents the activities of the gallery founded by Professor David Smith in 1971 on the campus of the California Institute of Technology in Pasadena, California. Documentation includes administrative records, business correspondence, programs and events, exhibition files, and printed material. There are also three films by artist Lillian Schwartz shown at the gallery. Also included are records of the Pasadena Gallery of Contemporary Arts, which was founded after Baxter Art Gallery closed by former director Jay Belloli.
Administrative records as well as business correspondence document the day-to-day functions of Baxter Art Gallery. The bulk of this documentation covers the period from 1978 to 1985, especially the period that Jay Belloli was gallery director. Most of the collection (9.0 linear feet) consists of Exhibition Files, which document nearly every exhibition held at the gallery from 1971 to 1985. Of note are detailed records regarding “25 Years of Space Photography,” the last exhibition held at Baxter Art Gallery in 1985 which toured internationally through 1990. After Baxter Art Gallery closed, Jay Belloli founded the Pasadena Gallery of Contemporary Art which was to be located at the Armory Center for the Visual Arts. One series of records document the planning that went into this gallery during its short existence.
Belloli, Jay; Pasadena Gallery of Contemporary Arts.; Schwartz, Lillian; Smith, David R., (David Rodman), 1923-; Art galleries, Commercial--California; Motion pictures (visual works); Space photography
- Administrative Records, 1971-1987; Series 1; 3.3 Linear feet Boxes 1-4
  Scope and Contents note
  Administrative records document the day-to-day functions of the Baxter Art Gallery. Included are various committee and project files, fundraising and grant proposals, as well as budgets and financial status reports. Also found are records of the Board of Governors, Friends of Baxter Art Gallery, and the Pasadena Art Alliance, a major financial supporter of the gallery. Additionally there are artwork loan agreements, files containing artist resumes, proposals for possible exhibitions, gallery guest books, and proposals from the early 1980s for a new gallery building. The bulk of the records in this series describe the gallery’s activities from 1978-1985. There is much less material covering the activities of the early-to-mid 1970s when David Smith was director.
  Also of note is a sound cassette recording and transcript of an interview with founding director David Smith conducted by director Jay Belloli in 1985.
  Arrangement note
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Account Ledger, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acquisitions, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advertising, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Association of Museums, circa 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Art Acquisitions Committee, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Art House Project, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Artist Information, circa 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Audiovisual Services, circa 1978-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Benefit Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Biographical Material on Michael Smith, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board of Governors - Guidelines and Planning, 1971-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
  - Board of Governors Meetings, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 18-21)
  - Calendar Annoucements, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - California Arts Commission, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Cash Flow and Deposits, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cash Receipts, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Charles Ulrick and Josephine Bay Foundation, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Committee on Arts, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Committee on Institute Art, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Development, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Dinner Guest Lists for Exhibition Openings, circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Distribution Lists, circa 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Draft Form Letters and Brochures, circa 1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Essay, "The Creative Arts and Twentieth Century Education", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Exhibition Expenditures, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Exhibition Receipts/Disbursements, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Financial Reports, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Friends of Baxter Art Gallery - Mailing Lists, circa 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Friends of Baxter Art Gallery - Membership, circa 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Friends of Baxter Art Gallery - Membership, circa 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Friends of Baxter Art Gallery - Newsletters, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Gallery Attendance, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Gallery Attendants, circa 1970s-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gallery Director Search, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gallery Divestiture, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Gallery Layout and Renovation, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gallery Sales, 1977-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Grant Brochures, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Grant Proposals, 1977-1979; 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Grant Writing Workshops, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Guest Book, 1980; 1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Guest Books, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 15-20)
  - Harry G. Steele Foundation, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Institute of Museum Services, Museum Assessment Program, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Internships, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Interview of David Smith on Early Years of the Gallery, 1985 May 29; 1 Sound cassettes Includes Transcript. (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
  - Juries, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Library of Congress Cataloging, 1974-1984 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Lists of Exhibitions, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Loan Agreements, 1973-1983 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art ARTEX Planning, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Museum Education Materials, circa 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Nancy Dau Yewell Memorial Art Fund, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, circa 1977-1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - New Gallery Building, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
  - Pacific Telesis, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Party Planning Guides, circa 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pasadena Art Alliance, 1978-1986 (Box 3, Folder 9-14)
  - Pasadena Garden Club, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Pasadena Men's Committee for the Arts, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Personnel and Job Applicants, circa 1970s-1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Petty Cash Worksheet, circa 1983 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Photography and Framing, circa 1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Possible Exhibitions, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 20-24)
  - Press Releases, circa 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Proposed/Revised Budgets, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
  - Publication Lists and Information, circa 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Receivables, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "Report on the Caltech Art Program 1968-1971", circa 1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Report, "Two Year Report on the Development of the Workshop and Gallery", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Roster - Associates of the California Institute of Technology, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Security, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Shipping, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Status Reports, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 35-44)
  - Status Reports, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1-14)
  - T-Shirt, "Save Baxter Art Gallery", circa 1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Word Processor, circa 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Work Orders, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Business Correspondence, 1969-1988; Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet Box 4
  Scattered business correspondence includes incoming letters from artists, members of the local Pasadena arts community, museums, galleries, and arts organizations. Also found here are a few copies of outgoing letters and inter-office memos. Letters may include attached printed material such as flyers and press releases, resumes, and news clippings. The bulk of the correspondence dates from 1982 to 1986, when Jay Belloli was gallery director. Researchers should note that the content of the correspondence found here may overlap with correspondence found within Series 1: Administrative Records and Series 4: Exhibition Files.
  Folders are arranged chronologically by year.
  - Business Correspondence, 1969-1976 (Box 4, Folder 18-22)
  - Business Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Business Correspondence, circa 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 24-33)
- Programs and Events, 1977-1986; Series 3; 0.4 Linear feet Boxes 4-5
  Found here are files documenting select programs and events sponsored by the Baxter Art Gallery. Included are lectures, fundraisers, trips, festivals, and film screenings. Documentation may include correspondence, published event materials, planning materials, and photographs. Of note are sound cassette recordings of talks by artist Alan Bean and art historian Gerald Nordland.
  Folders are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Film Screenings, 1977-1982 (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
  - Associates of the California Institute of Technology Gallery Preview, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Dinner and Discussion with Pontus Hulten, Richard Koshalek, and DeWain Valentine, circa 1981 (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
  - An Evening with Alan Bean: Artist and Astronaut, circa 1981-1982; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
  - Reception for Michael H. Smith, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Welcome for Jay Belloli "Nine/Twenty-eight/Eighty-two", 1982 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - A Bus Trip to La Jolla, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Excursion Holiday to Palm Springs, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Athenaeum Ball 1930, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 45-47)
  - Friends of Baxter Art Trip, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Gerald Nordland Lecture, 1984; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Olympic arts Festival, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - International Art Competition, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - "Over the Rainbow...", 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Smithsonian National Associates Lecture and Seminar Program, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Exhibition Files, 1968-1990; Series 4; 9 Linear feet Boxes 5-14
  Found here are extensive files documenting exhibitions held at the Baxter Art Gallery. A small amount of material also documents early exhibitions from 1968-1970 held on campus before the gallery was founded in 1971. The amount of documentation on each exhibition varies, and files may include correspondence, lists of artwork, loan agreements, planning notes, exhibition layouts, biographical material about artists, press clippings, exhibition catalogs, slides, installation photographs, and audio and video recordings.
  Also included are detailed records regarding “25 Years of Space Photography,” the last exhibition held at Baxter Art Gallery in 1985 which toured internationally through 1990. Found here are extensive planning documents and correspondence as well as individual files for each exhibition location.
  Folders are arranged chronologically by date of exhibition. Folders regarding the tour of “25 Years of Space Photography” are arranged alphabetically by location.
  - Various Exhibitions, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Paintings by Corda Zajac/Sculpture by Jack Zajac" (1969) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Various Exhibitions, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "Victor DuBois Collection of West African Art" (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
  - "The Hiroshima Panels" (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Artists-in-Residence" (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Tapestry West" (1971) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Lithographs: Daumier to Gemini" (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Aldo Casanova" (1972), 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Affiches De La Belle Epoque" (1972), circa 1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "Surrealism is Alive and Well in the West" (1972), 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14-17)
  - "Computer Halftones Exhibition" (1972), circa 1972 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - "Asian Art: Selections from the Eisenberg Collection" (1972) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Three Californian Artists" (1973), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - "Tijuanatomia" (1973) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "Ruth Asawa: A Retrospective View" (1973) (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - "Rhoda Kellog Child Art Collection" (1973), 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 23-24)
  - "Marvin Lipofsky" (1974), 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - "In the Japanese Tradition" (1974) (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "Ca. 90291" (1974), Includes 1 film reel. (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
  - "A California Turn On" (1974) (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
  - "General Whale" (1974), 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - "McCafferty DeLap" (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - "Arthur Ames/Douglas McClellan" (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - "Greene and Greene" (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
  - "McMillan/Chang" (1975) (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - "Hogarth, Lissaman, Morris, Rapoport, Zaima" (1975), 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - "Kinetic Art" (1976), 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 38-39)
  - "The Many Arts of Science" (1976), 1975-1976; 1969 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - "Lawton S. Parker: An American Impressionist" (1976) (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - "Contemporary Tapestries" (1976), 1972-1979 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - "In Search of Four Women/Four Cultures" (1976) (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - "Art Alliance Collects" (1977) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Watercolors and Related Media by Contemporary Californians" (1977) (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - "Michael Brewster" (1977), 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "Geoff Winningham/Jacqueline Thurston: Photographs" (1978) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "The Poetry of Systems" (1978) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Robert Cumming and William Wegman" (1978) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Hans Haacke" (1978) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Laddie John Dill" (1978) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Making Senses: A Proposal for a Children's Museum" (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Bryan Rogers: Timepieces" (1979), 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "A Painting Installation" (1979) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Bruce Richards" (1979) (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - "Nathan Oliveira: A Survey of Monotypes, 1973-78" (1979), 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 15-23)
  - "Visionary Drawings of Architecture and Planning" (1979), circa 1979 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "Trains and Boats and Planes" (1979-1980) (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
  - "Richard Tuttle" (1980), circa 1980 (Box 6, Folder 27-29)
  - "James Reineking" (1980), circa 1980 (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
  - "Jack Brogan: Projects" (1980) (Box 6, Folder 32-35)
  - "Architectural Sculpture" (1980), circa 1968-1981 (Box 7, Folder 1-15)
  - "Terry Allen (part of some in betweens)" (1981), 1969-1981 (Box 7, Folder 16-21)
  - "Site Buildings and Spaces" (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 22-23)
  - "Anti-Static" (1981), circa 1981 (Box 7, Folder 24-29)
  - "Anti-Static" (1981), circa 1981; Includes 1 videocassette: U-matic. (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - "Jerry McMIllan" (1981) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Peter Lodato" (1981) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Barry Fahr/Tom Jenkins/Paul Re" (1981), 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 5-7)
  - "Doo Dah" (1982), 1981-1982; Includes 1 videocassette: U-matic. (Box 8, Folder 8-10)
  - "Berenice Abbott" (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - "For Love and Money" (1982), 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
  - "Siah Armajani: A Poetry Lounge" (1982), 1982-1985 (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
  - "of no particular theme" (1982), circa 1982 (Box 8, Folder 17-20)
  - "Matter Memory Meaning" (1982) (Box 8, Drawer 21-22)
  - "Reliquaries: Richard Tuttle" (1982-1983), 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 23-25)
  - "Rockne Krebs" (1983), 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 26-27)
  - "Rockne Krebs" (1983), 1980-1984; Includes three sound cassettes of Rockne Krebs Seminar. (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
  - "Patsy Krebs" (1983), 1982-1985 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "Molly Burgess" (1983), 1982-1983; 1977; Includes 1 sound cassette of Molly Burgess interview. (Box 9, Folder 17-19)
  - "Caltech 1910-1950" (1983), circa 1981-1985 (Box 9, Folder 20-30)
  - "Caltech 1910-1950" (1983), circa 1981-1985; Includes 1 sound cassette of panel discussion. (Box 10, Folder 1-8)
  - "The Nicholas Del Pesco Collection" (1983), 1981-1984 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "The Nancy Yewell Collection" (1983) (Box 10, Folder 10-12)
  - "Fluxus, Etc." (1983), 1981-1986; Includes 1 sound cassette of interviews with Gil Silverman and Gwen Laurie. (Box 10, Folder 13-20)
  - "The Common American Bungalow" and "Tile, Stucco, Walls and Arches" (1983), circa 1983; 1978 (Box 10, Folder 21-24)
  - "Contemporary Ceramic Vessels" (1984), 1981-1984 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - "An Affair of the Heart" (1984), 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Five Artists Southern California" (1984), 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 5-9)
  - "John Altoon" (1984), 1982-1986; 1968; Includes 1 sound cassette of Henry Hopkins lecture regarding Altoon. (Box 11, Folder 10-21)
  - "Myron Hunt, 1868-1952" (1984), circa 1984; Includes 1 sound cassette of panel discussion. (Box 11, Folder 22-28)
  - "Arroyo Seco Release/A Serpentine for Pasadena" (1985), 1983-1988; 1977; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
  - "Painting as Landscape" (1985), 1983-1986 (Box 12, Folder 6-12)
  - "25 Years of Space Photography" (Box 12)
    - General Correspondence, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
    - Photographs of Exhibition Installation, circa 1985 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Planning Documents, circa 1983-1988 (Box 12, Folder 16-26)
    - Press Clippings and Publications, 1985-1989 (Box 12, Folder 27-28)
    - Publicity Photographs, circa 1974-1986 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Schedule of International Tour, 1986-1988 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Sound Recording of J. Belloli, Don Lynn at JPL Processing of Space Photographs, circa 1985; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Tour Refusals, 1984-1989 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Alicante, Spain, 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Baltimore, Maryland, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Barcelona, Spain, 1986-1989 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
    - Chicago, Illinois, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Coca-Cola Company, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Denver, Colorado, 1986-1989 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Eugene, Oregon, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Finland, 1987-1990 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Frankfurt, Germany, 1986-1989 (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
    - Fresno, California, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Hawaii, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - India, 1983-1989 (Box 13, Folder 16-25)
    - Linz, Austria, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Los Angeles, California, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Maarssen, Netherlands, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 28-29)
    - Mexico City, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Miami (Coral Gables), Florida, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Muskegon, Michigan, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - New York, New York, 1985-1987 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Ostend, Belgium, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Ottawa, Canada, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Republic of China, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Reston, Virginia, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Rochester, New York, 1985-1987 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Rome, Italy, 1986-1989 (Box 13, Folder 39-40)
    - San Francisco, California, 1985-1987 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Stockholm, Sweden, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Toronto, Canada, 1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Tucson, Arizona, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Utrecht, Netherlands, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
    - Vancouver, British Columbia, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Printed Material, 1971-1987; Series 5; 0.5 Linear feet Box 14, OV 16
  Printed material found here was primarily compiled by the directors of the Baxter Art Gallery from other arts organizations and museums. Included are publications regarding film programming at other organizations as well as museum brochures, newsletters, and reports. Material documenting Baxter Art Gallery includes scattered news clippings, exhibition and event flyers, and posters. Also found is one published Caltech planning report. Researchers should note that the bulk of the printed material regarding Baxter Art Gallery exhibitions is included within the Exhibition Files in Series 4.